PRASANTH JANARDHANAN

Product Development Specialist

prasanthmj@gmail.com | +91 9845422369 | https://prasanthmj.github.io/ | linkedin.com/in/prasanthmj/

Summary

15+ years of hands-on software product development experience. Certified Professional Scrum Product Owner. Hands-on full stack coding experience - Go (golang), Typescript, React. Experience working with customers gathering user stories, planning product roadmaps, and delivering value following agile methods.

FUNCTIONAL EXPERTISE

- Agile and Scrum
- User story mapping
- MVP and Product Roadmap Planning
- Continuous user feedback analysis
- Coding: Go, Typescript, React
- Devops: Kubernetes, Terraform, AWS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Simfatic Solutions,

simfatic.com

March 2009 - till date

Develops Software products for Process automation and workflow management

Senior Technical Manager

- Helped develop a work management product for a telecom tower construction company that included live streaming from multiple work sites.
- Worked with Software teams to implement user stories delivering the best value to the target customers
- Managed to integrate a smart support system right into the product that eventually helped reduce on-field errors users face.

Electronics For Imaging, Inc,

https://www.efi.com

April 2004 – January 2009

Electronics for Imaging (Nasdaq: EFII) builds software products for large-scale printing and publishing businesses.

Associate Architect

- Successfully designed and implemented a method to process very large PDF or PS files with more than 4GB in size with limited memory usage
- Worked with different product teams and external vendors to plan, design, and implement
 an integration platform using an industry-standard known as JDF (cip4.org). This integrated
 more than 4 separate information systems in different platforms as well as embedded
 systems and devices all working together in an automated manner.
- Worked on porting a Windows-only desktop product to Linux and Mac

• Started a refactoring initiative of an older codebase adding unit tests, bringing in platform portability, and better maintenance benefits.

LG Software India

http://www.lgsoftindia.com/

October 2002 – April 2004 The software development division of LG

System Analyst

Working on Software products - embedded as well as tools for the electrical/electronic types of equipment.

- Implemented a video player for the MMS clients in LG's feature phones.
- Lead the development of a product for estimating the load of HVAC (Air conditioning for large buildings) and generating quotations.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

1994-1998, Mahatma Gandhi University, Kottayam India.

Professional Scrum Product Owner, Scrum.org, 2022



Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)
The Linux Foundation, 2019



Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)
The Linux Foundation, 2019



OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

qUP

https://github.com/prasanthmj/qup

qUP is a background task processor with persistence support written in Go. It uses BadgerDb for persistence.

Chimes

https://github.com/prasanthmj/chimes

A JWT authentication library in TypeScript

OneCluster

https://github.com/prasanthmj/onecluster

A Terraform/Ansible project to build Kubernetes infrastructure on the Hetzner cloud

LANGUAGES

• English, Fluent